David Espinosa

David.Espinosa.21@gmail.com | +1 832-526-3365 | linkedin.com/in/david-espinosa5 | github.com/21david

SUMMARY

Professional software engineer with about 2 years of experience. Versed in all aspects of the software development lifecycle, with recent full-stack and back-end experience in JavaScript, Python, Java, and Rust. With practical experience solving technical problems and working in teams, I am ready to employ my talents and strong work ethic to tackle complex front-end and back-end challenges, innovate in a dynamic and collaborative environment, and contribute to your company's success.

SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript, Java, Python, SQL (MySQL), HTML, CSS, SASS, Bash/Zsh scripting, Ruby, Jade/Pug, Bootstrap, Jinja2, C++, Kotlin, Scala, Assembly Language
- **Knowledge:** Object-oriented programming (OOP), data structures, algorithms, Agile, software development lifecycle, unit and integration testing, deployment, version control, complexity analysis
- Tools and Environments: Node.js, VSCode, Git/GitHub, Chrome Dev Tools, Atlassian tools (Bitbucket, Jira, Confluence, Trello), AWS (EC2, EBS), IntelliJ, Eclipse, JCreator, MacOS, Windows
- Other: Fluent in Spanish, 90+ words-per-minute typing speed

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Pride Automation Inc. | Remote | Dec 2023 - Apr 2024

- Contributed to PRIDE View, a web application designed to facilitate and enhance the execution of complex and detailed procedures in industries such as space and oil, allowing customers such as NASA, Dow, and Intuitive Machines to have a smoother experience when running critical procedures such as landing the Odysseus lander on the moon
- Tech stack: Node.JS, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, Jade/Pug, Bootstrap, MySQL, Git, Bitbucket, Jira, and Confluence
- Enhanced user experience stability and consistency by fixing over 12 technical bugs, including UI and application feature bugs
- Reduced the learning curve for new users by creating detailed documentation for this application, guiding them into using its core features with step-by-step instructions and up-to-date images

Software Development Engineer

Amazon Web Services | Remote | Dec 2021 - Mar 2023

- Enhanced customer satisfaction on a global scale by contributing to a new EBS (Elastic Block Store, high-performance cloud storage for servers) encryption codebase in Python that drastically mitigated insufficient capacity problems faced by many customers
- Contributed to the company's financial goals by developing asynchronous Rust code for a new EBS
 encryption codebase which had a goal of re-engineering the encryption process to perform faster
 and safer, with projected savings of over \$50M a year
- Upheld service-level agreements (SLA) and enhanced performance by deploying updated encryption software with critical fixes and improvements to 30+ AWS regions, leading to a significant reduction in customer support tickets
- Streamlined deployment workflows by thorougly documenting deployment procedures
- Solved customer issue tickets during on-call shifts about one out of every five weeks

EDUCATION

App Academy Bootcamp

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

Full time bootcamp focusing on full-stack software engineering with Ruby on Rails

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Minor in Mathematics Lamar University, Beaumont, TX

Major GPA: 3.6 December 2020

ACHIEVEMENTS

Dean's List (2018, 2019, 2020), Hispanic Excellence Award (2019), International Dean's List Society (2018), President's List (2016)